lixiangisworking@gmail.com; 732-500-0284

SUMMARY

Technical skills: advanced knowledge in statistics specialized in regression, classifier, cluster, categorical analysis and multivariable analysis. Some related computer science such as graph algorithms and data structure.

Experience: built various models and hypotheses based on real life application data.

Personal: talented in mathematics, logical deduction, and critical thinking; good at imitation.

EDUCATION AND HONOR

Master in Statistics, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ

09/2012-10/2014

Bachelor in Statistics, Peking University, Beijing, China

09/2008-07/2012

Second prize in Chinese Mathematical Olympiad nationwide competition

2008

SKILLS

Programming languages: R, C++, SAS, python, MYSQL, hadoop, Java, lua

Documents: Microsoft office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Access),

Computer environments: Windows. Linux (Shell script)

COURSE-PROJECTS

- Built linear regression models (R language) after excluding outliers from data of "waste of production and land use" by Cook's distance, Leverage, DFFIT method, and DFBETA method.
 - -Identified the appropriate model by CP, AIC and BIC to catch the influencing factors in the data.
- -Applied classifier models on a PC game, to discover the relationship of various variables and the winning probability by logistic regression, SVM, decision tree, and naive Bayes methods respectively.
- Implemented a cluster model including ward, max, and min distance method to classify consumers, based on the linkage, supplier data and other variables. The distance function was based on the correlation matrix.
- Designed an experiment to do multiple comparison by Bonferroni-based methods.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst/Processing Clerk, Canaan Media, Branchburg NJ 08854

02/2015 to present

- -Carried out image processing work and trained OCR software to improve the accuracy of recognition.
- -Secured data by completing data base backups and saved data from CRYPTOLOCKER virus.
- -Developed software to automate data processing workflow.

Data Analyst Intern, UUsense, Shenzhen, Guangdong, China

07/2013 to 08/2013

- -Collected the APP error data, tested whether the data followed Poisson distribution and built a kernel density estimation.
- -Estimated the users' frequency of taking out their phones, reading or playing games in metro after work and compared to other time intervals.
- -Proposed a hypothesis that the error rate of an input time interval A in a day was more than the rate of another input time interval B. Then constructed a fisher-exact-test model (R language) to test this hypothesis.
- -Applied the test to every single day in recent 3 months, drew the conclusion and created a data visualization.
- -Gave my colleagues a lecture about how to apply the statistics to their works, including making a reason based on the Simpson paradox for asking more data from the clients.

Intern, Cinda Securities, Beijing, China

07/2012

-Made a hypothesis and a test that some equities' prices followed the Brownian motion.

Intern, Citibank

variances.

07/2011

- -Estimated the tendencies of some prices investments by linear models and estimated the risks by standardized
- -Completed linear combination portfolios for an individual based on the estimations above and his willing.
- -Wrote some lua scripts to diy unofficial cards with effects by notepad++ for an open source game software YGOPRO and adjusted its cheating AI scripts occasionally.